Hello everyone, in this video, we will introduce the basic principle of the application method of layers.
In order to easily understand the application method of layers, open the texture surface to distinguish the correct version of the fabric.
Now we have two pieces of fabric. Under the stable state, the white fabric is on the outer layer of the pink fabric.
The initial layer of each sheet is 0.
Now apply a positive layer to the pink fabric.
After starting to simulate, because the current layer is higher than the white fabric, the pink fabric is simulated outside the white fabric.
The layer can not only be set as a positive, but also set as a negative.
After being set as a negative, the layer of pink fabric is smaller than the layer of white fabric.
The front of the white fabric touches the back of the pink fabric.
Because the layer of white fabric is higher, it will pass through the back of the pink fabric.
When the layer of white fabric is stable, the layer of pink fabric returns to 0.
There will be no more gap between the layers.
Next, let's take a look at the fabric in other situations.
Let's take a look at the simplest situation.
The two fabrics turn in the opposite direction and turn to the back.
Now we look at the two layers from the ground.
These two layers are stacked on the ground from the back.
Let's set the pressure of the pink fabric as positive.
After starting to simulate, there is no difference.
In fact, this is the same as the two layers in the opposite direction.
In essence, the front of one layer is in contact with the back of another layer.
When a layer of relatively low fabric touches the back of a layer of relatively high fabric,
it will not pass through.
But when the layer of pink fabric is set to negative,
the front of the white fabric is in contact with the back of the layer that is lower than it,
and it will pass through.
Next, let's take a look at the other situation.
The front of the two layers is in contact with the front of the two layers.
Then let's modify the layer of one of the layers.
After starting to simulate, we will find that the simulation has not changed,
and it is still stable.
When the two layers are only in contact with the front of the two layers,
no matter how many layers are in contact with each other, they will not pass through.
Whether it is positive or negative layers,
the front of the two layers will not pass through.
Next, let's take a look at the situation when the back is pasted on the back.
It is the opposite of the situation when the front is pasted on the front.
As long as the layers of two layers are different,
when the layers of the two layers are in contact with each other,
they will pass through each other until the front touches the front.
As long as the layers of the two layers are in contact with each other,
no matter how many layers are in contact with each other,
they will pass through each other.
When we make a tie or knot,
we usually encounter a problem,
that is, the tie cannot be worn under the tie.
Generally, it is possible that a costume is made,
and then a knot is made and poured in.
When we start to simulate,
there will be conflict and instability,
so we have to freeze the costume version first.
If it is just a positive layer for the tie,
then the tie version cannot be worn.
This is because the tie and the tie have the back pasted on the back.
In this case,
both versions will pass through the opposite side of each other.
But this front of the tie
also touches the back of the other version.
However, we have only changed the layer inside.
After opening the simulation,
the layer between the sheets will be very unstable
and even the sheet will be squeezed out.
For this situation,
our easiest way is to let the tie stand up first,
and do not fold it.
The tie or tie is not involved in the simulation,
and there is no collision.
Now we are going to turn the tie over.
Usually the tie is facing the back.
The inside part of the simulation is manually stretched out,
so that the sheet can stand up.
After folding it,
freeze the inside and outside sheets.
Now we can see that the inside of the sheet is facing the outside.
Here we have a seat,
and after checking,
it also faces the outside.
After confirming that the tie
only penetrates the front and outside sheets,
We give it a positive layer to let it pass through
After passing through, stretch this board
Look carefully at this bar, it keeps moving up
In fact, it is because the board is too short
Stretch it a little and re-multiply
If there is a twisted position after adjusting the board
You can use the selection grid tool to adjust it
Select the selection grid tool
In the 2D window, select the twisted grid part
And rotate it horizontally in the 3D window
After rotating and opening the simulation, there is no twist
Reduce the impact thickness
Can reduce the air thickness around the board
Once back to the collar
Otherwise, the collar will be turned down
That is, the back of the collar touches the front of the collar and will pass through
After that, you can fold the collar part
First, you can use the selection grid tool to adjust it
But if there is a penetration, it may cause the simulation to be unstable
The easiest way is to continue to hardening the collar
Turn it over manually
In order to prevent the effect of the made collar
Can freeze the collar plate
Hold it separately and drag it inside
If it is not easy to turn it over
You can use the hardening function
You can turn it over faster
Then untie it and simulate it together
That's it
Next, let's look at another example
That is, the penetration of the shirt and the belly button
When the shirt penetrates the belly button
We will find that there are a lot of points in this week
There will be many situations when the shirt penetrates
For example, the back to the back, the back to the front, etc.
If you apply the layer directly, it will lead to this
In many cases
The direction of the sheet through the board is not stable
If you simulate it directly
The clothing will be in the area of penetration
It's relatively small
Just wear it out
Add the layer and simulate
Just like the previous explanation
It's not stable when I simulate
In order to prevent instability, we need to adjust the top coat.
First, reverse-actualize the uniform so that it no longer participates in the simulation.
Then, hide the uniform.
Next, select the four body parts and reduce the tail-axis, so that the uniform is tight on the virtual model.
Then select all the uniform parts and activate them.
Next, load the uniform.
Now the uniform is not in the simulation.
Since the uniform is now very tight, it is basically attached to the innermost part of the body.
Therefore, most of the body parts are not in the simulation.
Remember to apply layers here.
Otherwise, there will be some instability due to the seam seam.
Then start the simulation.
After the simulation is stable, you can gradually return the shrink rate to 100%.
After the simulation is stable, turn your body over to the original position.
And the overall result will be 0 from the simulation.
Now let's see how it will work if the waistband is not applied.
To apply a waistband, first, turn the waistband over.
Look at the simulation and you will see that if the folding part itself is not stable and the belt is not evenly organized, the belt will be pulled by the folding.
In the process of pulling, because the layer is relatively low, the belt panel will be rolled in and it will not be stable.
So the most stable way is to add layers to the outer part of the two panels.
See you in the next video, bye bye.
Thank you for watching.